<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>danielmatsuda</title><link>https://danielmatsuda.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on danielmatsuda</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:45:07 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://danielmatsuda.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>(summary ver.) Analyzing 65,000 Japanese news articles with AWS</title><link>https://danielmatsuda.github.io/summary-ver.-analyzing-65000-japanese-news-articles-with-aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 05 Jul 2021 18:45:07 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://danielmatsuda.github.io/summary-ver.-analyzing-65000-japanese-news-articles-with-aws/</guid><description>I study Japanese, so I decided to create a Japanese word frequency list using news articles as the source data. To do this, I made a serverless ETL pipeline that processed 65,000 articles.
This post briefly summarizes my project. You can find all the code in my Github repo. You can also read the longer version of this post here, where I explain my motivations, design decisions, and code in more detail.</description></item><item><title>Japanese News Project</title><link>https://danielmatsuda.github.io/japanese-news-project/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Jul 2021 19:00:27 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://danielmatsuda.github.io/japanese-news-project/</guid><description>I made a serverless ETL pipeline to record all the words from 65,000 Japanese news articles. Then, I found the most frequent 5,000 words and visualized them. This post explains why I made the pipeline, how I designed it, and how it works. You can find all the code in my Github repo.
Table of contents Why analyze Japanese news articles? My project strategy Requirements Design Development: Finding articles Development: Sending articles to queue Development: Extracting and processing article text Development: Storing, aggregating, and exporting Storing words Aggregating and exporting words Results and next steps Conclusion Notes: Estimating costs Why analyze Japanese news articles?</description></item><item><title>About</title><link>https://danielmatsuda.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://danielmatsuda.github.io/about/</guid><description>About Hello, I&amp;rsquo;m Daniel. I recently changed careers from Japanese translation to software development. In my new role as an engineer, I value the impact, constant learning, and collaboration afforded to me.
Besides foreign languages and software, I also love modern hip-hop dance and reading.</description></item></channel></rss>